<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Publications on Roberta Rosa Valtorta</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/publications/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Publications on Roberta Rosa Valtorta</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.140.1</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/publications/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Development and validation of the Gender Stereotypes in Sport Scale (GSSS) in an Italian soccer context</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/publications/gender-stereotypes-in-sport-scale/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/publications/gender-stereotypes-in-sport-scale/</guid>
      <description>This study develops and validates the Gender Stereotypes in Sport Scale (GSSS), an instrument assessing gender stereotypes in sport, with a specific focus on soccer.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 restrictions and sense of humanness: the role of human needs threat</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/publications/restrictions-and-humaness/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/publications/restrictions-and-humaness/</guid>
      <description>This study examines how COVID-19 restrictions increased the sense of threat to human needs, leading to higher self-dehumanization and lower concern for humanity</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inequality perception and preferences globally and locally - Correlational evidence from a large-scale cross-country survey</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/publications/inequality-perceptions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/publications/inequality-perceptions/</guid>
      <description>This study uses a large, cross-country survey to examine how people&amp;rsquo;s attitudes toward domestic economic inequality influence their views on cross-country economic disparities.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why are some countries rich and others poor? Development and validation of the Attributions for Cross-Country Inequality Scale (ACIS)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/publications/cross-country-inequality-scale/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/publications/cross-country-inequality-scale/</guid>
      <description>This paper aims to develop and validate the Attributions for Cross-Country Inequality Scale (ACIS), which assesses how people explain cross-country economic inequality.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Measuring subjective inequality: Development and validation of the Perceived Economic Inequality Scale (PEIS)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/publications/perceived-economic-inequality-scale/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/publications/perceived-economic-inequality-scale/</guid>
      <description>The main goal of this research is to develop and validate the Perceived Economic Inequality Scale (PEIS), an instrument measuring individuals&amp;rsquo; perceptions of economic inequality at the national level.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On the indirect link between virus anthropomorphism and health behavior: Evidence from the pandemic</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/publications/anthropomorphism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/publications/anthropomorphism/</guid>
      <description>By taking advantage of the COVID-19 pandemic, the present research investigates the implications of thinking about a virus in human-like terms for individuals&amp;rsquo; health-related behaviors.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigating the link between biological dehumanization and indirect aggression</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/publications/dehumanization-and-aggression/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/publications/dehumanization-and-aggression/</guid>
      <description>By considering the most dehumanized social groups in Italian society (e.g., homeless people, prisoners, and immigrants), this research explores the link between biologization (i.e., a form of dehumanization in which others are perceived as contagious entities) and indirect aggression.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why might women justify dating violence? The role of men&#39;s sexual objectification of their romantic partners within heterosexual relationships</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/publications/dating-violence/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/publications/dating-violence/</guid>
      <description>This research investigates the associations between men&amp;rsquo;s partner-sexual objectification, women&amp;rsquo;s self-objectification, and both partners&amp;rsquo; attitudes toward dating violence.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A twofold subjective measure of income inequality</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/publications/twofold-subjective-gini/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/publications/twofold-subjective-gini/</guid>
      <description>This article introduces a twofold subjective Gini coefficient that combines perceptions of social class and pay structure to more accurately measure beliefs about income inequality.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gender stereotypes and sexualization in Italian children&#39;s television advertisements</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/publications/children-and-ads/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/publications/children-and-ads/</guid>
      <description>This study examines gender stereotypes and sexualization in Italian television advertisements aimed at children. The findings reveal that gender stereotypes are still prevalent in Italian children&amp;rsquo;s television commercials and that girls are more sexualized than boys.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The impacts of COVID-19 on the relationship between perceived economic inequality and political action among socioeconomic classes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/publications/covid-and-inequality/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/publications/covid-and-inequality/</guid>
      <description>This study explores how the COVID-19 pandemic influenced the relationship between perceived economic inequality and political participation by considering Italian individuals from different socioeconomic classes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When workers feel like objects: A field study on self-objectification and affective organizational commitment</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/publications/objectification-and-commitment/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/publications/objectification-and-commitment/</guid>
      <description>This study examines how objectifying job features in a supermarket setting lead to self-objectification and lower organizational commitment among workers with different roles.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effects of objective and subjective indicators of economic inequality on subjective well-being: Underlying mechanisms</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/publications/inequality-and-well-being/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/publications/inequality-and-well-being/</guid>
      <description>This study examines how objective and subjective measures of economic inequality affect individuals&amp;rsquo; subjective well-being, focusing on how anger and feelings of economic vulnerability mediate this relationship.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Street harassment and its negative psychological outcomes in an Italian university population</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/publications/street-harassment/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/publications/street-harassment/</guid>
      <description>This research assesses the frequency of street harassment and explores its links to negative psychological outcomes, such as anxiety and self-objectification.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Loneliness, escapism and identification with media characters: An exploration of the psychological factors underlying binge-watching tendency</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/publications/binge-watching/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/publications/binge-watching/</guid>
      <description>This study examines the psychological factors that contribute to binge-watching tendencies, examining how loneliness, escapism, and identification with media characters influence the tendency to watch multiple TV episodes in one sitting.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Burnout and workplace dehumanization at the supermarket: A field study during the COVID-19 outbreak in Italy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/publications/burnout/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/publications/burnout/</guid>
      <description>This study explores the psychological effects of the COVID-19 emergency on supermarket workers in Italy, focusing on burnout levels and the relationship between burnout and employees&amp;rsquo; workplace experiences in terms of dehumanization.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Intergroup biologization and outgroup prejudice in the time of COVID-19</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/publications/covid-and-prejudice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/publications/covid-and-prejudice/</guid>
      <description>This study explores how the COVID-19 emergency influenced biologization (i.e., the perception of others as contagious entities) and outgroup prejudice in Italy, offering insights into the psychological dynamics at play during the pandemic.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Seeing others as a disease: The impact of physical (but not moral) disgust on biologization</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/publications/disgust-and-biologization/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/publications/disgust-and-biologization/</guid>
      <description>This study investigates the link between physical disgust and biologization (i.e., the perception of others as contagious entities) using both explicit and implicit measures of biological dehumanization.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Together apart: The mitigating role of digital communication technologies on negative affect during the COVID-19 outbreak in Italy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/publications/together-apart/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/publications/together-apart/</guid>
      <description>This study explores how the use of digital communication technologies during the COVID-19 lockdown in Italy helped mitigate the negative psychological effects of forced social isolation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pictures as weapons: Delegitimization strategies in the visual propaganda of Forza Nuova</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/publications/pictures-as-weapons/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/publications/pictures-as-weapons/</guid>
      <description>By using the theory of delegitimization as the theoretical framework, this study examines how posters used by the Italian far-right party Forza Nuova (2000-2018) promoted the marginalization and exclusion of certain groups.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do self-objectified women believe themselves to be free? Sexual objectification and belief in personal free will</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/publications/objectification-and-free-will/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/publications/objectification-and-free-will/</guid>
      <description>This study explores the consequences of sexual objectification, showing that objectifying comments lead women to self-objectify, which in turn diminishes their sense of personal free will.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The dirty side of work: Biologization of physically tainted workers</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/publications/biologization-workers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/publications/biologization-workers/</guid>
      <description>This research investigates how dirty work environments contribute to increased feelings of disgust and biologization (i.e., a form of dehumanization in which individuals are perceived as contagious entities) of physically tainted workers (e.g., garbage collectors).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dirty jobs and dehumanization of workers</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/publications/dirty-jobs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/publications/dirty-jobs/</guid>
      <description>By exploring laypeople&amp;rsquo;s dehumanizing perceptions of stigmatized workers, this study demonstrates that different types of occupational taint evoke distinct dehumanizing images.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#39;The body and soul emotion&#39; - The role of disgust in intergroup relations</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/publications/the-body-and-soul-emotion/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/publications/the-body-and-soul-emotion/</guid>
      <description>The study explores how different forms of disgust (physical vs. moral) affect aggressive intentions and dehumanization in intergroup relations.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Objectified conformity: Working self-objectification increases conforming behavior</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/publications/objectified-conformity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/publications/objectified-conformity/</guid>
      <description>This study explores whether self-objectification from performing objectifying tasks increases conforming behavior, indicating that participants who engaged in a high objectifying task self-objectified more and conformed more to others&amp;rsquo; judgments.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Workers as objects: The nature of working objectification and the role of perceived alienation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/publications/workers-as-objects/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/publications/workers-as-objects/</guid>
      <description>This study investigates working objectification, demonstrating that factory workers are more likely to be associated with object-related words and perceived as having less agency and experience compared to artisans.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The eternal feminine: Gender stereotypes and sexualization in television advertisements</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/publications/eternal-femminine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/publications/eternal-femminine/</guid>
      <description>This study examines gender stereotypes and sexualization in Italian television advertisements, revealing that women are portrayed as younger, more engaged in domestic roles, and more sensual, while men are depicted as sportier, more independent, and more competent.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
